OpenAI Codeex is an autonomous AI coding
agent designed to read code bases,
execute commands, run tests, and
complete software engineering workflows
across multiple tools and environments.
In this course, you will learn the
fundamentals of how to use codecs for
software development and more.
If you've spent any time around software
engineering this year, you've probably
heard the name OpenAI Codeex more times
than you can count. Some developers
swear it's the best coding tool they've
ever used. Others say it finally
delivers on the promise of AI agent. And
then there are the people who open it
for about 5 minutes, close the tab, and
wonder what all of the excitement was
about. The difference really isn't Codex
itself. It's understanding how Codeex is
meant to be used and that is exactly
what this course is about. You will
learn about what Codeex is, who it is
meant for, how to use it, and some of
the amazing things you can do with it.
At the end of the course, I have a
surprise for you. So, be sure to stick
around. And in case you're wondering,
yes, this entire edit, the complete
intro section was made by Codex itself.
So, it is part of some of the things you
can do with it. So, keep that in mind.
Okay. So, if you don't already have
Codeex installed, what I'd urge you to
do is you first of all head on to this
website, which is the official OpenAI
website. By the way, I have a link in
the description below so you can access
it. Once you are on here like this, you
choose your specific OS installation and
you just simply download and install.
I've already done that, so I'm not going
to go through the same process again.
Okay. So once you've had Codex installed
and I've logged in and I've gone through
the entire onboarding phase, you're
supposed to land on an interface like
this or the light mode of this. Now if
this is your first impression, you
probably will be thinking this looks
weirdly minimalistic. You're right. By
the way, it's only a left pane with the
work area on this side. But now that
we've gone through the installation
process, let's talk about pricing,
right? So, Codex allows you to use GPT
5.5 even on a free account, right? So,
you are literally paying nothing and
you're getting access to GPT 5.5.
However, there's limited access to it.
So, I think the most value you get for
your money is by probably subscribing to
the pro, which is either the $100 a
month or what I'm currently using, which
is the $200 plan. Let me show you. So
you come on here, usage and billing,
right? So as you can see the 200 over
here. Now the reason I only chose the
200 is because I often use it heavily
and more than half the time even with
the $200 I barely hit my limits. You can
see I even have two resets here. The
reset is basically if you fail to hit
the limit then it's going to roll over.
They're going to offer you a reset.
[snorts]
So, if you're not going to be using it
heavily, you probably should subscribe
to the $100 tier or lesser than that. If
I had had such information before, I
probably wouldn't have gone so high. But
now I'm addicted to it. So, I'm
definitely going to renew with a 200.
All right. So, now that that part is
also cleared on the left side pane,
there's a couple of things you need to
take note of. So, this is practically
like Chpt itself. Let me close this down
over here. So all you are seeing on the
left side pane is the new chart which
basically allows you to converse with it
like you would in Chpt, right? There's
also search here which is
self-explanatory. And then there's shed.
This part will prove vital and very
important more than half the time on the
basis that you can automate tasks here.
So as you can see I have three
automations that are currently paused.
one that was running every hour. One
that was running every day. I don't want
to run it. One that was running every
day. This one was running every day,
right? But currently I've paused them
all. So basically, you can simply
automate anything inside of codeex. And
it's great with machine use. It can look
up anything on your device. It can send
messages even through your WhatsApp.
Right? So there's really no bounding of
this AI agent. Now to create an
automation you just simply click here
create via chat and you can see it gives
you some sort of a starting point.
So it gives you some sort of a starting
point. So it says let's set up a shadow
task together whatever whatever or you
can just simply go on and start type hey
I need you to set an automation that
runs in the next 1 minute. That just
prompts me that hey my automation run.
So basically I'm going to send this over
and it's going to boot up an automation
for me. Now while that is going on let
me explain the other part too. So you
can see there's a project side here and
there's the chart side here. The chat is
basically you conversing with it without
actually saving it in any actual folder
like the project side. Inside a project
everything you are creating is going to
be stored in here. So, it's sort of like
a collection to organize all of your
thoughts. Now, we just got a response
from the automation we set up. It says
done. I set one time automation for
about 1 minute from now. That will
prompt. [snorts] Right. Okay. So, we're
going to wait for the automation to run.
But while we wait, let me explain
further some of the things you can see.
So, in here, I'm going to create a new
chat by clicking the new icon over here.
And as you can see, we get a fresh
interface to start work from. Now, if
you don't already have a project in
here, what you do to create one is by
hovering on the project side and then
clicking this button over here, which
will trigger up either to create a new
one or to use an existing folder. So, if
you want to create a new one, you simply
click next, name it, and then save. But
since I'm already inside an empty
folder, I'm not going to do that. Okay.
So remember we set an automation about a
minute ago. So as you can see the
automation that we set up run now and as
you can see it was shed and run. Hey my
automation run which you can see here.
Hey my automation run. I deleted the
completed one time automation so it
won't fire again. So the possibility of
this is completely endless. You can run
any sort of automation supposeding once
like asking it to send an email to your
boss every morning or contact somebody
or reach out for leads or customize your
YouTube channel and and gathering your
content creation ideas trying to
assimilate yourself with what the
breaking news are all of that there's
absolutely no restrictions on this part.
>> [snorts]
>> Right now to the most important part,
let me show my face on here for this
part. So for the most important part,
this plug-in section is going to be very
instrumental in your use of codeex. So
majorly the ones I use are primarily
superbase and notion, right? Notion is
basically like obsidian to me. So it's
like me taking notes inside of notions.
So I do not like to store context inside
the AI agent itself or the chat window
because at some point it's going to get
cumbersome. It's going to get very large
if you're working on large code bases,
right? So if it gets really big, you are
at a loss because these AI agents could
forget if it exceeds their context
window. So I like to store all of the
relevant information inside notion but
inside notion all of the context will be
in there. So in the instance where the
AI needs a certain type of information,
it just goes into the notion, pulls it
out, use that sort of data and the work
is done. Right? So this plugins is what
I was talking about primarily. There
there are a whole lot in here even
Figma, Versel, GitHub, there's so many
more, right? So basically what you're
going to do is say you want to tie Gmail
to your codeex, right? You just simply
click on install over here and it's
going to pull up the connector for you.
So inside the connector, you just simply
click connect to Gmail and it's going to
open up in your browser and try to
connect with your actual Gmail account.
But I do not want to connect it with my
Gmail at the moment. So I'm not going to
do that part yet. So I'm going to close
out of this. But once you are set up
with it, you're going to see that it is
fully connected to it and you can
interact with it completely from the
chat conversations. So I've already
connected with superbase. So you can see
try chat like this and you can see it
tags superbase in here which is the
plugin. So use superbase to set up and
protected routes for my app. Right? So
you can customize this however you wish.
There's literally, like I keep saying,
it's endless. The possibilities are
endless.
So, before we progress any further into
the course, there are a couple of things
I need to address before we can move on.
As you can see from the UI here, there
are a couple of changes here. Now, the
footage you had seen is from a much
older version of Codeex. However, the
principles stay the same. I mean you
still have the plugins, you still have
the shled, the new chat, you still have
the projects over here and as well you
are able to chat and converse with it.
So primarily those things remain
constant and are practically
transferable and I'm I'm guessing it's
going to remain that way throughout all
of the updates of codeex. Right? So the
new changes are first of all now it is
no longer a standalone application
anymore. Now it is primarily the chbpt
desktop app. You can see from the logo
change over here this logo you can
change it back to the codeex logo that
you had seen before and as well you can
switch in between normal charg.
So when you change it to charg over here
you are able to specify between two
states either to use it as a chat app
which is primarily the same as the web
version or you can use it as work which
primarily gives you more of a practical
use case. So in the instance where say
you have like five different files that
you'd want to compress into one the work
is best for that. It's able to you it's
able to take it a step further as
compared to the chat. Now the codeex
version though is primarily for software
or I mean software related tasks. Right?
So that is the two distinctions that is
primarily inside codeex. Now now as you
can see over here there's also pull
request. This ultimately brings the
feature in GitHub into the codeex app
itself. So you are not going to have to
switch between codeex and GitHub and
then make pull requests and then try to
close them off or whatever. When you
click in the pull request here, it opens
up all of the pull requests you have on
your active Git account which is linked
to your app here. Right? So as you can
see this is my actual GitHub repo.
You'll understand this from later in the
course when I actually build out the
surprise I told you about at the start
of the tutorial. So you can see I
already have one PR over here which is
from a year ago. Once you click into it,
you'll be able to see the comments.
Whatever you would want to do, you can
do straight from the Chibbt desktop app.
You can also merge changes. Whatever
you'd want to do, right? So that is one
of the changes that has reflected inside
Codex. Now as well we have sites in here
now. primarily if you've used Versel or
Netlifi before this is like a a a
scratch off of all of those things right
so now CEX allows you to deploy your
websites or web apps inside of Codex by
giving you a charg link so I created
this yesterday so let me show you what
it looks like I primarily asked it to
let me open it up for you to see over
here I primarily asked it to create me a
creator road map as a YouTuber to get to
my first $1 million as a YouTuber.
Right? So that is what you are seeing
over here. So basically what you do is
you just call in the sites like an
actual plugin. So you do add sites like
this and it's primarily going to call in
the sites feature. You just click enter
like this and then you can add your
prompt and then it's going to handle it
just as you are seeing my prompt over
here. Right? So I asked it to create a
website that tells me how to get to my
first million dollar as a YouTuber and I
asked it to prioritize great design
right. So this was the outcome it gave
me and it as you can see from the domain
link over here it has the chip attached
to it. So this is deployed onto's
own infrastructure. So this is an actual
published website right now when you
click into it over here. Let me show
you. Now when you click into it over
here you're able to see the metrics like
analytics or whatever. So this could be
an actual deployed platform for you. You
can track the traffic that it's
received. I mean primarily like an
actual dashboard for your website.
Right. So that is primarily what the
site is for. Now let's move on to the
actual important things inside of
codeex. Let me close this over here like
this. So the most important part of
Codeex, the part where you'll be working
in more than half the time is this work
area over here. Now when you look at the
work area, there's a couple of things to
take note of. First of [snorts] all is
this voice recorder which allows you to
dictate and send in prompts using your
voice. There are other alternatives that
I like to use. I do not like to resort
to this a lot. I use Whisper Flow, so
more than half the time I'm not using
this feature. Another thing to take note
of is this model selector over here.
This allows you to switch between
models. So whether so Terra Luna or
previous models like the 5.5 or 5.4,
right? Do note though that 5.6 sold here
is their flagship model. What that means
is it's the most competent chip model
out there. It rivals uh Fable 5 from
Claude Code, right? So soul is the most
competent one here with Terra being the
intermediate and Luna being a slightly
less cheaper and a well economical way
of running GPT 5.6. Right? So that is
primarily all that you need to know
regarding the models themselves.
However, you could also specify the
efforts in here. So you could have
either between light up until ultra with
ultra meaning it's going to consume a
lot of your tokens and it's ultimately
going to produce better results.
However, more than half the time you may
not even have to use it. For my sake for
instance I like to resort to either
extra high or simply keep it at medium.
This design you see over here was done
with a medium and as you can see it's
pretty decent in itself. Right? Good. So
that is also regarding the efforts. You
could also specify the speed over here
by either transitioning between standard
or fast with fast being as it implies
it's going to produce the results much
faster and also it's going to use up
your tokens quite fast too. Now another
thing I wanted to cover though is now I
am currently on the $20 plan. The
previous footage you had seen was the
$200 plan. So in my experience
with the tokens optimization it's quite
decent. You are not going to have to
complain a lot about the $20 plan. With
the 200, I was barely hitting my limits.
I was just throwing money, burning cash
primarily. That is how come I've
switched to the $20 plan. And it's quite
decent. I I have to be honest, you can
do so much with it. One disadvantage
about that is once you run out of uh
your limits, your weekly or hourly
limits and you have to top up, it's
quite expensive because what you can do
in the 5hour gap window. The credits if
you top up say 20 or 50 could run out
much faster than your actual limit,
right? Which is primarily this 5hour
limit or even your weekly limit, right?
So that is primarily all that you need
to know regarding the model selection
and everything relative to that. Right?
So you could this is a good visual of
all that I just showed you. Right?
Another thing though to note is the
permissions section over here. So there
are three main ways you can transition
into. There's the ask for approval which
primarily ask you whenever it needs to
run something on the terminal or use the
internet or access external files
generally. So it's always going to ask
for approval before doing anything
outside of the codeex charg app itself.
Right. Now, the app approve for me is
also another thing to note because this
allows you to be able to run some
commands, but if it detects that the
command is potentially unsafe, then it's
definitely going to ask you to approve
of those actions. But I like to keep it
at full access because more than half
the time the things I am doing are not
really on safe. And another thing is I
do not have anything to lose on this
specific machine. So, if anything goes
haywire, there's nothing I'm losing. But
you need to be careful if you are ever
going to sell it to full access as I
have. I'm just going to leave it there
for now. Now, this plus sign over here
allows you to add context into your
prompt, right? So, you're able to tag
files and folders in here. You able to
trigger on goal and plan mode. We'll get
to these two later in the course. They
are very good and they deserve their own
sections. So, I'm going to delegate that
to the later part of this tutorial. And
as well, you can access the plugins that
you've added. So, once you add a plugin
here to access them, you can use this
plus over here. I'll show you other ways
to access them as well. So, you [snorts]
can choose between all of your plugins
here, your apps, even the sites. I mean,
I added this in as a skill. Or you could
even open up your site in here. This is
the actual domain link that we just saw,
which is over here like this. As you can
see, it's the same domain link here,
right? So
the there's practically everything you
have in Codex, you can access it here
like that, right? You can even access
some of your conversations. You can
access your chats and files all over
here. Now, another thing I want to show
you is slash commands, right? So
basically all you got to do is bring a
forward slash like this and it allows
you to tag in a lot of things right.
First of all another thing you would
want to know is the fast which I showed
you over here. You could trigger it by
using a slash command or even the MCPS
or models or pets. Let me turn this on
for you all to see. So this primarily
gives you a codeex a codeex pet. It
triggers on a codeex pet over here for
you to see. As you can see, here is
mine. And once you're working in some
sort of codebase or you're doing some
work, it's going to show you like a
visual of what is happening inside of
your codebase, right? So, it's going to
show you when you're running command,
say you're running through O or you are
on boarding or whatever, it's going to
show you here. So, you get like a
visualization of all that you're doing
inside of the Chbt app. But I don't like
to use it. So, and I've also found that
it tends to make my machine lag a bit.
So, I just generally like to turn it
off. When it comes to codeex, generally
there are three ways to run commands,
right? You could either use the slash
command, you could use the at sign,
sorry, the add sign, which generally
allows you to mention things inside of
your conversations, or you could use the
dollar sign to call in skills. So, the
dollar is primarily for skills, right?
So as you can see I have a lot of skills
in here. When you see this personal tag
with them it means they are skills that
you have you may have created or CEX may
have created for you in the course of
running a command. Right? So all of
these personal ones are ones that I
created or Codex created for me. There
are also ones that are system which
comes pre-built with codeex itself. As
you can see here are some of them like
the image generation which is nothing
new because Chibbt has great image
generation. You're able to open open eye
docs. You see the system ones are the
ones that come pre-built inside of chex
app right as well. You can see there's
one with the app tag which primarily
calls in the plugins or things you may
have installed. Right? So I want to dive
in specifically to the skills side. So
I'm going to do forward slash over here
and show you some of the skills that
I've created. Right now the most
important ones to note though when you
do slash commands is slash plan and
slashgo. These two are very instrumental
in your use of codeex. Primarily about
80% of codeex everything you're going to
be doing in codeex revolves around these
two which I'm going to describe later.
Now while it is going on and getting
things done, let me specify a couple of
things. As you can see, this prompt is
sort of vague to write. But then it's
going to be able to understand based off
of the skill that we have added, which
is this milliondoll editorial skill.
Now, what this does when it is creating
the skill is that it takes everything
all of the approach that it took to
create the design and then it adds it in
as a MD file. So that becomes our skill,
right? So every time we're needing it
and then we just tag it in, it's going
to take this prompt and then add this MD
file which is going to be like another
set of instructions that gives it an
understanding of how you are expecting
it to reproduce the result. I hope that
was clear enough for you to understand
how to be able to create reusable
skills. But we're going to wait for this
so much so that you understand that the
difference is just as we expected it to
be. The implementation is the same as
the previous design, right? So a perfect
use case of this would be say you are
constantly creating you are working in a
team right and then let me use myself as
an example right I need to communicate
with the rest of the team based on the
metrics of my YouTube channel based on
the number of people that reached out to
collaborate with us the paid
sponsorships all of the niche niche
details all of the nitty-g gritties
right to be able to send a decent design
say when I like this design I could just
have this added in as a skill since it's
already a skill in here. When I want to
communicate with the team, I'll just ask
it to go and then pull all of the
details on my YouTube channel and then
create it using this milliondoll
editorial design and then have it sent
over to the rest of the team. Right? So
to take it even a step further, I could
automate it so much so that I just come
into the shadowed over here create a
workflow around it that every month at
the end of every month say on the 27th
of every month it should send this over
to the rest of the team so that they can
review it too. So they are always um
kept in the loop right so primarily that
is one use case I am not able to think
out wide on the various use case
hopefully you know how you're going to
use it for yourself but primarily that
is the end of the story there
okay so after 11 minutes and some
seconds it's able to generate the
visualization for us so as you can see
this is nothing different from this one
which is the actual skill. Right? So the
design is primarily the same thing and
you as you can see it gives you a strong
message to
mean a perfect road map. It even add
stages to scale the signal. I mean
practically an actual road map to get it
done and it use the actual design that I
had specified with the slash scale
command. Right? So that's entirely what
I was expecting. Now if you try to open
into this, I'm suspecting that you'll be
able to even add it in as a skill as a
site. Right? So as you can see, this
over here will completely turn this
thing that you've made into an actual
accessible website just like this with a
similar domain like this. But I don't
want to waste my prompt on that because
you primarily get the point I am trying
to put across. Right? So a perfect use
case would be when you are having
repetitive work to do, you just have to
add that repetitive task. You create a
model that is completely going to be
reusable and then you just add it in as
a skill. So every time you need to do
that skill again, you need to make that
change again. Every time you need to
make that work again, you simply call
that skill with a new information and
then send it through as a prompt and
it's going to edit have it ready for
you. So you can send it over to whomever
you'd want to send it to. Back to the
two that I am very prudent about. These
two are completely the entirety of
Codeex itself. These two will get you
through Codeex more than 80% of the
time. And this is how you're going to
trigger them all by doing slash P L A N.
This is for turning on plan mode. And
plan mode ultimately runs through your
thoughts process. So you just say you
want to build maybe a housekeeping app
or a calorie counter or something,
right? You just explain it in like you
would in your normal prompt. Once you
send it through, Codeex will try to see
the vision that you have behind it. It
will try to understand everything that
you've put across. If there are
redundancy or there's something that
seems unclear, it's going to come up
with series of questions right in a
cycle. So say in the first cycle would
ask about two questions to properly
ascertain what you're trying to tell it
to do. And then once it understands it
will take all of those context together
again try to understand if there are any
questions or redundancy again it will
bring it to you again for you to specify
what you would want to get it to do.
Right? So it will continually come back
to you. It's not going to be so
kimbersome that it becomes annoying
though. So it's just running running
through your mind to understand what you
think. Once it has ascertained what
you're trying to get, then it's going to
come up with an implementation plan with
everything that I was able to put
together and then submit it to you for
you to review it again. This time if you
love it, you can just go on and see
proceed with the implementation plan or
simply just edit what you want to edit.
You'll understand that in a minute
because I'm not just going to talk to
you about it and not show we'll actually
work through that. I also want to talk
to you about SL goal, right? So
there's a bit of a distinction between
the two, right? SL goal, however, is
when you actually have a target in mind.
So you have like an end goal in mind
which I said to trigger you just do
simple /go like this and click enter and
as you can see it has been triggered
here right so go mode comes after you've
already decided what you are trying to
build so instead of asking coders to
think about a project you are the one
telling it what the end goal or the
result should be I mean it's in the name
goal plan mode goal mode it's basically
self-explanatory
Right? So you're basically saying that
you have given it the destination. So it
should keep working towards that
destination until it is achieved. A
typical example would be if you are
building an inventory system or say a
LinkedIn profile scanner or something,
right? A typical end goal would be that
the app should be able to analyze
LinkedIn profiles. The app should be
able to accept LinkedIn links to be able
to analyze them, right? The app should
be able to recommend changes. Those
sound like actual goals, like end goals,
right? So, Codex is going to iteratively
build on that. So, it's going to
recursively improve until that said
goal, all of the metrics you gave it are
completely achieved and then it will
present you the completed work. A slight
distinction amongst the two is you
cannot have plan mode and go mode all on
at the same time. Let me show you. So,
we already have plan mode on here. As
you can see, if I do /go like this and
enter, you see plan mode gets removed
and replaced by go mode, right? So, you
cannot have the two on at the same time.
You can only toggle on one at a time.
So, in my case, what I usually like to
do is I start with plan mode, right? So,
I may have all of the information that I
think I have, but then when I send it
over as plan mode, Codex is going to
analyze everything that I had. given it
run through some of the questions that
it may have for me. Once it ascertains
what I am trying to do, it's going to
come up with an implementation plan and
I simply copy that implementation plan
and then have it sent over with the /go
command over here. So, it's going to run
it through run it through until that
goal is achieved. And finally, when I
have an MVP, then I end the topic. All
right. So now I want us to get into the
actual surprise that I keep mentioning
even at the start of this tutorial. So
the surprise ultimately is to build out
a game specifically a flappy bed type
game. But we're not copying the entire
implementation because the original
Flappy Bird game is basically a bed that
is to be kept afloat by tapping as it
goes through tunnels, right? So rather
than having to type, we're trying to be
ingenious. So we are using our voice
instead of tapping through those
tunnels. Right? So to keep the bed
afloat, you just have to use your voice
as it is being opposed by gravity. So
this is the exact prompt I sent in that
I want a a build of the Flappy Bird game
and then I sent it in with the slash
plan active. Right? So once I sent that
through it ran a couple of tools and
then it came back with the first round
of questions. So it came back the first
round of questions was three-fold and it
asked these questions right. So when I
had answered it took that context back
in and then came back with another
series of questions which were also
three right so I answered those
questions too. Basically it gives you
whether you want to go with a
recommended or two different options or
if you don't like any of them you can
specify which approach you would want to
use. I'm sorry that I don't get to show
you that part. But basically that is it.
And then it came back with another
question which I had answered too. So
that is the question over here like
this. And then once it's assimilated all
of the questions and got a proper
context of what I want, it took all of
that in and came back with an
implementation plan. So this
implementation plan I could have sent it
through on its own because this type of
game is not really cumbersome. It's not
that big. It could have oneshotted it on
its own, right? But I want to purely
demonstrate how the goal works. So I
stopped the implementation plan from
going through and then I copied the
prompt over here like this. And that
same prompt I pasted in here with the
/go command. Let me show you what I did.
So I did I pasted it in like this and
brought the /go over here like this and
then activated it and simply sent it
through. So that is what you are seeing
over here like this. I'm going to remove
this before I make the mistake of
sending it through again. So that is
what has been running for the past 23
minutes. That is ideally the very
specific goal I gave it and it's
constantly running right now. You can
see it's edited a couple of files,
created even an image for us, something
like a cover art ads we're going to use
for the game, and now it's still
running. So once it has fully oneshotted
this code, we're going to test it out on
our own. And then I'm going to open
source this work. I mean, I'm going to
keep it on my repo for free and have a
link in the description below so you
guys can access it. Ultimately, you can
choose to monetize this by either
selling it out or even publishing it
onto Google Play Store or App Store.
Right? For Google Play Store, the
pricing is $25 and then for the App
Store, it's $99 per year. Right now, the
only reason why I'm keeping this
particularly minimalistic is that if I
do the entire build and then push it out
there for you guys to put it on App
Store or Play Store, they are definitely
going to reject you guys because it's
like some sort of circumvention. You are
all putting out the same bit of code out
there and Apple is just going to term it
as a cliche, so to speak, right? So I
want you guys to have this for yourself
and however you choose to use it whether
to monetize or to even keep it yourself
to engage with it and then to keep you
active when you are low [snorts]
that is entirely up to you. So once it
is done I'm going to demonstrate it and
then I'll show you how to access the
repo from the description below.
Given us our first generation. I am sort
of having some little bit of issues with
it, but I just want to test it for you
guys to see first before I make any
revisions to it. So, let's get into it.
So, it it gives you a countdown when you
have to keep shouting
already.
Not so good. Okay. Hey, hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey, hey. Sorry about the
noise.
I may have to skip that for now. So, we
just got updates on our game, right? So,
this was the follow-up prompt I had sent
in. So, I want us to test it together.
So, literally deployed it onto the GPT
hosting that I talked about before. So,
let me just open it in my browser.
Yeah. And right now it's only visible to
me, but once this video is published,
well, right after testing actually, I'm
going to actually open it up so that
everybody could access it and play it
too. And once I deploy it onto my repo,
I'll make sure to add a readyto use
conversion from this website to an
actual mobile app. so much so that you
can just copy it, paste it inside of
your codeex and then it it will convert
it into an actual mobile app which is
through expo. So you'll be able to have
it on iOS as well as Android. So once
you buy your account on the app store,
which is the app store developer
account, and then the play store
account, you can simply just deploy it
on there and then you'll make money off
of it. Right? So, I'm going to test it
out for you all to see. So, I'm going to
enable my microphone over here and then
start the flight.
Ah. Oh, sorry about that. Uh
uh.
Oh. Okay. So, it's like for it to be
able to hover, you see this thing over
here? It's picking up my voice, right?
So I think for it to be able to hover,
it needs to stay constantly inside the
third bar, right? So let me try again.
Ah,
that was bad. That [snorts] was bad.
Well, what's software engineering
without a sense of humor?
Let's go again.
Ah!
A!
>> [laughter]
>> That was dumb, bro. [snorts] Oh, at
least we just got the the highest score
in the game so far. So, literally that's
what you have there. Let me just deploy
it on to my GitHub repo. Note though
that I've already connected it on here.
So literally all I have to do is I just
ask it to.
[music]
All right. So Codex just pushed
everything onto the GitHub repo that we
had specified. So I want to show you how
you guys can access it. So literally
I'll have this repo linked in the
description as well. So you just come on
here like this and first of all it has a
read me that is user friendly. So you
could just read through and then it will
show you how to get started and install
it basically. And as well it comes with
an expo conversion prompt. What this
will show you is it's a ready to copy
and paste prompt that allows you to
paste this inside of codeex or code or
whatever AI agent that you're using. And
literally it's going to convert this
entire thing that we had done into an
actual mobile app that is both iOS
friendly and Android friendly. So once
you have the application you can deploy
it onto app store or Google play and
then monetize it from there. Right? So
literally all you have to do is paste
this in there. And as well I want to
cover something real quick. All of this
thing that we've done in this tutorial
was just to get you started and to
understand the fundamentals of Codex. I
did not show you an actual workflow to
be able to build slopless applications.
You got to have a workflow. All right.
So, in the next video, which is also
going to be with free code cam, I'm
going to come on here again, right? And
literally we'll be centered on workflows
because these tools themselves are
really competent. They have incredibly
powerful. But then if there's no proper
workflow around them, you're definitely
going to be generating a lot of slop or
literally you'll be ending in cycles
because you'll just be hoping for the
best on every prompt, right? But if
indeed you're going to build something
that you're going to put in front of
real users, then most certainly you need
to have a workflow. So in the next video
I'm going to take you from one step
which is literally from A to Z on how to
build actual production ready systems
using workflows. So if you like the idea
of that, most certainly do leave a
comment in the comments box letting the
entire Free Code Camp team understand
that you would want to see that. And as
well, do not forget to like, do not
forget to subscribe to Free Code Camp
because quite literally they have a lot
of incredibly useful projects on here
and as well you can find me on Skyro
getting text. So do step by sometime. I
just figured some of you guys would also
want to play the game. So, right now,
because the visibility is just set to
only me, I'm going to change it to
public so that everybody else can also
be able to play and have it linked in
the description below. So, if you want
to play it, just go on and play it. I
hope you have fun. See you in the next
one. Yeah.